<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="en">
	<title>Scrambled Brains for Breakfast</title>
	<subtitle>A place to throw my scrambled brains against the wall to see what sticks.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://example.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://example.com/"/>
	<updated>2024-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://example.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Sam Westwood</name>
		<email>sam@thewestwoods.us</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Snorkeling</title>
		<link href="https://example.com/blog/2024-02-25-snorkeling/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://example.com/blog/2024-02-25-snorkeling/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;snorkeling&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Snorkeling &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/2024-02-25-snorkeling/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now a T-mobile Home Internet customer. It uses 4G LTE and 5G cellular networks to provide internet connectivity. They provide you with a cellular modem/router with a wifi hotspot and a couple of ethernet ports. I figured out how to disable the wifi and connected it to the WAN port of my UDM Pro. Easy-peasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some trade offs. There is some variability in the signal quality, which translates to extra latency some of the time. The cellular networks also use CG-NAT and &lt;strong&gt;T-mobile does not provide a public IP address.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could get around this by setting up some &lt;em&gt;Cloudflare tunnels&lt;/em&gt;. They are easy and work great. The main problem is that I want to control my own SSL certificates. Cloudflare creates a wildcard certificate for subdomains (*.mydomain.io), but only root level subdomains. Inside my LAN I use sub-subdomains. For example, &lt;em&gt;service.computername&lt;/em&gt;.mydomain.io. For publicly exposed services I prefer using the same URL inside my LAN and over WAN, and Cloudflare tunnels are not able to give me that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My LAN is now diving beneath the depths CG-NAT. I need a snorkel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-txt&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-txt&quot;&gt;    public ip (vps)

     |  s  |
/&#92;/&#92;/|  n  |&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;/&#92;
     |  o  |  Deep Waters of CG-NAT
     |  r  |
     |  k  |
     |  e  |
     |  l  |
     &#92;     &#92;________
      &#92;  tailscale --&gt; DMZ --&gt; LAN
       &#92;____________
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, I’ve got a VPS with a public IP. It connects to my DMZ proxy server through my Tailscale tailnet. The VPS forwards any traffic it receives on ports 80 and 443 to the proxy server. &lt;strong&gt;¡Viola! A snorkel!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;forwarding-packets&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Forwarding Packets &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/2024-02-25-snorkeling/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial thought was to turn my VPS into a router. I tried using iptables to forward ports, but I’m not very good at writing rules and had a few problems. I couldn’t figure out how to forward packets through tailscale. 🤔 After some more searching around the interwebs I found an old program called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samhocevar/rinetd&quot;&gt;rinetd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rinetd-setup&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;rinetd setup &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/2024-02-25-snorkeling/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;rinetd&lt;/em&gt; silently forwards tcp and udp traffic. It is found in most linux package managers. I’m using an Ubuntu server, so I installed it with an easy &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install rinetd&lt;/code&gt;. The configuration file is found in &lt;code&gt;/etc/rinetd.conf&lt;/code&gt;. The main section looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-bash&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;# bindaddress bindport connectaddress connectport&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;137.184&lt;/span&gt;.89.83 &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;100.86&lt;/span&gt;.67.77 &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;137.184&lt;/span&gt;.89.83 &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;443&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;100.86&lt;/span&gt;.67.77 &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;443&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;bindaddress&lt;/code&gt; is the public ip of the VPS, and the &lt;code&gt;connectaddress&lt;/code&gt; is the tailnet address of the proxy server. Easy. After updating the configuration, run a quick &lt;code&gt;systemctl start rinetd&lt;/code&gt; and you are set. No need to mess with forwarding rules. It just works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to make more coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Diving into the deep</title>
		<link href="https://example.com/blog/2024-02-24-diving-into-the-deep/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://example.com/blog/2024-02-24-diving-into-the-deep/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;diving-into-the-deep&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Diving into the deep &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/2024-02-24-diving-into-the-deep/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I had a little &lt;em&gt;snafu&lt;/em&gt; with Xfinity. I have been an Xfinity customer for more than a decade. In my area, it has really been the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; option for high-speed internet connections. I have always felt uneasy about the leverage that Xfinity has had over the market. I hate the equipment fees, and the lack of good customer service. I refused to use an Xfinity router or modem, instead opting to buy my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago they implemented a data cap, and I — untrusting of the monopoly-induced power of the company — purchased a UDM Pro SE and started measuring my own data usage. Throughout these years the usage reported by Xfinity was typically higher than my own measurements, but within a reasonable margin of error. However, that changed in December of 2023. During that month the UDM Pro measured about 800GB of throughput, and Xfinity reported a whopping &lt;strong&gt;2400GB&lt;/strong&gt; of usage! &lt;strong&gt;Three times more&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked in to the nearest Xfinity store intending to ask for a service ticket. &lt;s&gt;However, I was told in no uncertain terms that &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the Lord God of Xfinity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in it&#39;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mighty Glory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;omnicient knowing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; source of &lt;strong&gt;truth&lt;/strong&gt;. My own paltry attempt at measuring throughput was meaningless. &lt;em&gt;Xfinity&#39;s&lt;/em&gt; mighty judgement would not be questioned! How dare I question it?&lt;/s&gt; &lt;em&gt;Okay, okay... those were not their exact words, but they are not &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; hyperbolic either.&lt;/em&gt; They refused to submit a service ticket on my behalf, and told me to quietly pay the bill of over $300, &lt;s&gt;and that I should leave with a &lt;em&gt;smile&lt;/em&gt; on my face&lt;/s&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instead I left with a solid resolve to cancel my account.&lt;/strong&gt; I saw the commercials for T-Mobile Home Internet, advertised for $50 a month with &lt;em&gt;unlimited&lt;/em&gt; data usage. It actually ended up being slightly cheaper than that since I am an existing T-mobile customer. It offers better speeds than any other ISP in my area besides Xfinity, and I am happy with my choice (so far). A week or so later I closed my Xfinity account and I am not looking back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T-mobile home internet brings some additional challenges. Namely, I am now sitting behind a messy CG-NAT. I do not have a public IP address to access my home network. If you google around a bit, most people solve this by using a &lt;em&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/em&gt; tunnel. I have used them before, and it is an easy and effective solution, even providing ssl certificates automatically. But, &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; prefer doing things the &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; way. It&#39;s the only way to learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is getting quite long. Now that you know the backstory, I will post the &lt;em&gt;exciting&lt;/em&gt; details of my own personal solution to these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to make more coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
